Register of the European Technical Advisers Records, 1918-1923
Hoover Institution Archives
European Technical Advisers Records,
1918-1923
XX006
European Technical Advisers
69 manuscript boxes. (28.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, statistics, and financial records, relating to railway operation, fuel production, and other aspects of economic reconstruction in Austria, Poland, Czechoslovakia, and Yugoslavia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Fuel--Austria.; Fuel--Czechoslovakia.; Fuel--Poland.; Fuel--Yugoslavia.; Railroads--Austria.; Railroads--Czechoslovakia.; Railroads--Poland.; Railroads--Yugoslavia.; Reconstruction (1914-1939)--Austria.; Reconstruction (1914-1939)--Czechoslovakia.; Reconstruction (1914-1939)--Poland.; Reconstruction (1914-1939)--Yugoslavia.; Austria.; Czechoslovakia.; Poland.; Yugoslavia.; United States--Foreign relations.
Historical Note
The European Technical Advisers was a private American advisory organization created in the spring and summer of 1919 by Herbert Hoover, head of the American Relief Administration, in response to concerns that post-peace treaty demobilization of the Central European network of military advisers would leave a serious vacuum in the coordination of highly-complicated economic and technical functions. Technological novelty, governmental disorganization and international antagonisms, as well as wartime disruption of industrial infrastructures, were major problems threatening the rapid re-establishment of economic stability in the area.
Mr. Hoover suggested the establishment of a consulting organization in each country, supported by the funds of the respective governments (usually taken from reparations remittances). The technical advisers were agents of the countries in which they worked; however, their efforts were supported by offices in New York and Paris, staffed by American Relief Administration (A.R.A.) personnel, and supervised by a Board of Trustees. Mr. Hoover was the first Chairman of the Board, but upon his becoming Commerce Secretary in the Harding Administration, this function was divided between W.B. Poland and Edgar Rickard. Colonel James A. Logan, Jr. headed the Paris agency, which served as an important liasion between the technical advisers, the A.R.A., the Reparations Commission and other Allied authorities headquartered in Paris.
The technical advisers were primarily responsible for generating reports and recommendations, but they often served important executive functions as well, particularly in negotiating with other countries and in conferring with officials and businessmen. Theoretically, each mission had a technical adviser, a food adviser and a financial adviser; in actuality, the focus was on mining, manufacturing, transportation, and industry. Of prime importance was the condition of the railways: the technical advisers worked on problems relating to procurement of adequate rolling stock, transportation of food and fuel, incorporation of regional networks, and evaluation of tariffs, import and export licensing, rates, administrative organization, and schedules. The advisers also dealt with similar problems relating to the production and distribution of coal and oil, as well as other commodities (textiles, timber, sugar, grain); their coordinative efforts also greatly aided the A.R.A. in providing relief aid within these areas. After two years, sufficient progress had been made to allow the official termination of the missions in late 1921-early 1922.
Series Description
- EXECUTIVE OFFICE FILES, 1919-1923. (Box es 1-14)
  Correspondence, telegrams, budgets, invoices, and other financial materials, memoranda, reports, charts, statistics, clippings, speeches and writings, meeting minutes, contracts and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by country.
- MISSION TO AUSTRIA OFFICE FILES, 1919-1923. (Box es 14-29)
  Budgets, accounts, ledgers and other financial materials, passports, telegrams, correspondence, miscellany, contracts, reports and memoranda. Arranged by subject.
- MISSION TO CZECHOSLOVAKIA OFFICE FILES, 1919-1922. (Box es 29-32)
  Correspondence, budgets, accounts and other financial materials, reports, telegrams, contracts, statistics, miscellany, memoranda, speeches and writings, printed material and meeting minutes. Arranged by subject.
- MISSION TO POLAND OFFICE FILES, 1918-1922. (Box es 32-62)
  Speeches, typescript and printed articles, blueprints, book orders, correspondence, clippings, budgets, accounts and other financial materials, maps, charts, meeting minutes, passes and passports, miscellany, reports, statistics, telegrams, contracts, and schedules. Arranged by subject.
- MISSION TO THE KINGDOM OF THE SERBS, CROATS AND SLOVENES (YUGOSLAVIA) OFFICE FILES, 1919-1920. (Box es 63-69)
  Meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, memoranda, contracts, maps, financial materials, miscellany, printed material, diagrams and blueprints. Arranged by subject.
Container List
- EXECUTIVE OFFICE FILES, 1919-1923
  - General (Box 1)
    - General. Logan, James A., telegrams and letters (Folder 1-2)
    - Financial material (Folder 3-5)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 6)
    - Organization (Folder 7)
    - Personnel (Folder 8)
    - Supplies. Army surplus (Folder 9)
  - Files relating to the mission to Austria
    - General
      - General. Liquidation of the mission. Includes materials relating to negotiations with Austrian Government, sale of equipment and other matters (Folder 10-13)
      - Articles. Railway Age (Folder 14)
      - Financial material. Includes bank balance, monthly statements, invoice charges, and other miscellaneous material (Folder 15-18)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 19)
      - Organizational materials
        - Causey, Colonel, Chief of Mission (Folder 20)
        - Causey, Colonel, visit to U.S. (Folder 21)
        - Equipment (Folder 22)
        - Finance of mission (Folder 23)
        - Office of mission (Folder 24)
        - Logan, James A., Jr. (Folder 25)
        - Policy of mission (Folder 26)
        - Trustees and joint managers (Folder 27)
      - Records, shipment of (Folder 28)
      - Reports (Box 2)
        - Final (Folder 1)
        - General conditions (Folder 2)
        - Resume of work of mission (Folder 3)
        - Weekly (Folder 4)
      - Salaries (Folder 5)
    - Austrian government
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Foreign Affairs Ministry (Folder 7)
      - Railways Ministry (Folder 8)
    - Burgenland (Folder 9)
    - Coal
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Use of pulverized coal (Folder 11)
    - Coke (Folder 12)
    - Financial and economic conditions (Folder 13)
    - Geneva Conference (Folder 14)
    - Goode, Sir William (Folder 15)
    - Industrial conditions (Folder 16)
    - Italian King's visit to Vienna (Folder 17)
    - Plebiscite, West Hungary (Folder 18)
    - Political conditions (Folder 19)
    - Portorose Conference (Folder 20)
    - Proclamations (Folder 21)
    - Railway mission, French and British section (Folder 22)
    - Reparations
      - Milch cows (Folder 23)
      - Reparations Commission (Folder 24)
    - Telegraph system (Folder 25)
    - Tourists (Folder 26)
    - Transportation
      - General. Condition of railways (Folder 27)
      - Reorganization of state railways (Folder 28)
    - Upper Silesia (Folder 29)
  - Files relating to the mission to Czechoslovakia (Box 3)
    - General
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Clippings (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and memoranda (Folder 3)
      - Financial materials (Folder 4-6)
      - Organizational materials
        - General (Folder 7-8)
        - Closing of office (Folder 9-10)
      - Reports (Folder 11)
      - Supplies (Folder 12)
    - Automobiles (Folder 13)
    - Czechoslovak government
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Masaryk, Jan. Report on the Russian situation (Folder 15)
    - Food conditions (Folder 16)
    - Portorose Conference (Folder 17)
    - Transportation (Folder 18-19)
    - Raw materials needed (Folder 20)
  - Files relating to the mission to Poland
    - General
      - General. Speeches and writings by Col. Barber (Folder 21-22)
      - Clippings (Folder 23)
      - Correspondence and memoranda (Folder 24)
      - Financial materials (Folder 25-29)
      - Organization (Box 4)
        - General (Folder 1-3)
        - Closing of mission (Folder 4-6)
      - Personnel, appreciation letters (Folder 7)
      - Purchasing and shipping
        - Cars, locomotives and cranes (Folder 8-9)
        - Electric generating sets (Folder 10)
        - Explosives (Folder 11)
        - Fertilizers (Folder 12)
        - Gasoline passenger cars (Folder 13)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 14)
        - Pile drivers (Folder 15)
        - Rails (Folder 16)
        - Rules and forms for accounting (Folder 17)
        - Shipping Board claims (Folder 18)
        - Tractors (Folder 19)
        - Waste (Folder 20)
      - Reports
        - General
          - Final (Folder 21)
          - Monthly (Box 5, Folder 1)
          - Progress (Folder 2)
        - Inspection trips
          - General (Folder 3)
          - Oil fields. Ferguson report (Folder 4)
    - American-Polish Chamber of Commerce (Folder 5)
    - Coal (Folder 6)
    - Corn (Folder 7)
    - Explosives from Germany (Folder 8)
    - Financial and economic conditions (Folder 9)
    - Food conditions. Durand report, 1920-1921 (Folder 10)
    - Foreign Trade Finance Corporation. Relates to loans (Folder 11)
    - Forest and timber lands (Folder 12)
    - General conditions (Folder 13)
    - Genoa Conference (Folder 14)
    - German-Poland settlement (Folder 15)
    - Guaranty Trust, Polish agreement (Folder 16)
    - Mining (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Oil (Folder 2)
    - Polish government
      - Cabinet (Folder 3)
      - Commerce and Industry Ministry (Folder 4)
      - Consul General in New York City (Folder 5)
      - Polish Official Purchasing Bureau (Folder 6)
    - Political conditions (Folder 7)
    - Tests and standards (Folder 8)
    - Transportation
      - General conditions (Folder 9)
      - British-Polish sale of equipment (Folder 10)
      - Car shops at Ostrowa (Folder 11)
      - First railway built after Armistice (Folder 12)
      - Freight traffic agreement between Poland and Hungary (Folder 13)
      - Maintenance of way situation (Folder 14)
      - Opening new railway (Folder 15)
      - Railway control of Danzig terminal (Folder 15)
      - Reconstruction program (Folder 16)
      - Rolling stock (Folder 17)
      - State Railway Council (Folder 18)
      - Tables of railway traffic (Folder 19)
      - Wagon needs (Folder 20)
    - Upper Silesia
      - General (Folder 21)
      - Chemical industry (Folder 22)
      - Coal mines (Folder 23)
      - Coke ovens (Folder 24)
      - Economic conditions (Folder 25)
      - Industrial conditions (Folder 26)
      - Iron
        - Foundries (Folder 27)
        - Half products (Folder 28)
        - Mines (Folder 29)
      - Lead foundries (Folder 30)
      - Lead and silver foundries (Folder 31)
      - Mechanical and machinery industry (Folder 32)
      - Mining and industrial region (Folder 33)
      - Open hearth furnaces, production of (Folder 34)
      - Plesbiscite (Folder 35)
      - Polish Economic Delegation at Paris Peace Conference, 1919 June (Folder 36)
      - Political conditions (Folder 37)
      - Production (Folder 38)
      - Raw materials, production of (Folder 39)
      - Rolling mills (Folder 40)
      - Steel plants (Folder 41)
      - Textile, mineral, paper and other industries (Folder 42)
      - Transportation
        - General (Folder 43)
        - Wagon situation (Folder 44)
      - Zinc
        - Foundries (Folder 45)
        - Rolling mills (Folder 46)
      - Zinc and lead
        - Production and export (Folder 47)
        - Roasting furnaces, zinc and lead ores (Folder 48)
  - Files relating the the mission to South Russia (proposed?) (Folder 49)
  - Files relating to the mission to the Kingdom of the Serbs, Croats and Slovenes (Yugoslavia) (Box 7)
    - General
      - General. Miscellaneous papers (Folder 1-4)
      - General. Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
      - Financial material (Folder 4)
      - Financial material (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
      - Office files (Folder 3)
      - Personnel material
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Coe, C.S. (Folder 5)
      - Purchases
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Automobiles and parts (Folder 7)
        - Brushes and brush holders (Folder 8)
        - Locomotive cranes (War Department) (Folder 9)
        - Railroad material (War Department) (Folder 10)
        - Telegraph and telephone, cranes (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Wrecking cranes (War Department) (Folder 2)
      - Reports
        - General
          - General (Folder 3-4)
          - Atwood, William G. (Folder 5)
        - Conferences with Yugoslav officials (Folder 6)
      - Statistics. General information (Folder 7)
    - Concessions, financial, industrial (Folder 8)
    - Electric lights, tramways (Folder 9)
    - Government (Folder 10-11)
    - Mining
      - General
        - General (Folder 12-13)
        - Reports (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
      - Coal (Folder 3-5)
      - Iron (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Salt (Folder 2)
    - Oil (Folder 3)
    - Railways (Folder 4)
    - Shipping
      - General. Transportation matters and claims (Folder 5)
      - Cadillac (Folder 6)
      - Charter of two French steamers (Folder 7)
      - Insurance on cargoes in France (Folder 8)
      - Lost tires (Folder 9)
      - Right axle shift and cushion (Folder 10)
      - Ships
        - Allies (Folder 11)
        - Altmarek (Folder 12)
        - Lake Eckhart and Lake Fontana (Folder 13-15)
        - Lakeside (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - Santarem (Folder 2)
      - Typewriters (Folder 3)
      - United States War Department. Includes awards, purchases, copies of contracts and data relating to cancellation of war debt contract (Folder 4-6)
- MISSION TO AUSTRIA OFFICE FILES, 1919-1923
  - General (Box 14)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - A-B (Folder 7-9)
        - C-H (Box 15, Folder 1-8)
        - I-P (Box 16, Folder 1-10)
        - Q-Z (Box 17, Folder 1-9)
      - United States government (Box 18)
        - Commerce Department (Folder 1)
        - War Department (Folder 2-3)
    - Financial materials
      - General. Budgets, accounts and ledgers (Folder 4-6)
      - Vouchers
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 7)
        - 1920-1922 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
        - 1922 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Meeting materials (Folder 2)
    - Memoranda (Folder 3-4)
    - Miscellaneous. Passports, passes, reservations, recommendations and introductions (Folder 5)
    - Press reviews (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Statistics (Folder 2)
    - Telegrams
      - General, 1919-1920 (Folder 3-6)
      - British Food Mission, Vienna (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Commercial (incoming, Vienna) (Folder 2)
      - HAM (?) (incoming, Vienna) (Folder 3)
      - HAM (?) (outgoing, Vienna) (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Incoming, Vienna (Folder 2)
      - Incoming, Vienna (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Outgoing, Vienna (Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 3)
      - Press dispatches, London (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Agreements. Austrian-Hungarian and Austrian-Czechoslovak commercial agreements (Folder 2)
  - American National Red Cross (Folder 3)
  - American Relief Administration (Folder 4)
  - Austria (Folder 5-6)
  - Bate, F.B. (Folder 7)
  - British Food Mission (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Burgenland (Folder 2)
  - Cement (Folder 3)
  - Coal
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Austria (Folder 5-7)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 8)
    - Hungary (Folder 9)
    - Poland (Folder 10)
    - Railroads (Folder 11)
    - Upper Silesia (Folder 12)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 13)
  - Communications
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Austria (Folder 15)
  - Copper (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 2)
  - Danube arbitration (Folder 3)
  - Explosives (Folder 4)
  - Food
    - Austria (Folder 5-6)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 7)
    - Hungary (Folder 8)
    - Italy (Folder 9)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 10)
  - Hungary (Folder 11)
  - Imports (Folder 12)
  - Magnesite (Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 14)
  - Missions (Folder 15)
  - Oil
    - General (Folder 16)
    - Austria (Folder 17)
  - Poland (Folder 18)
  - Reparations Commission (Box 28)
    - American Delegation (Folder 1)
    - British Delegation (Folder 2)
    - French Delegation (Folder 3)
    - Italian Delegation (Folder 4)
  - Romania (Folder 5)
  - Sacks. Relates to empty sacks for grain transport (Folder 6)
  - Save River Bridge, Yugoslavia (Folder 7)
  - Strikes (Folder 8)
  - Sugar (Folder 9)
  - Trade reports (Folder 10)
  - Traffic. Primarily weekly reports (Folder 11)
  - Transportation
    - Austria (Folder 12)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 13)
    - Convoyers (Folder 14)
    - Hungary (Folder 15)
    - Locomotives (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Poland (Folder 2)
    - Railroad cars (Folder 3)
    - Southern Railway (Sudbahn) (Folder 4)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 5)
  - Yugoslavia
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Remittances (Folder 7)
- MISSION TO CZECHOSLOVAKIA OFFICE FILES, 1919-1922
  - General (Box 29)
    - Correspondence
      - General. Daily file, 1920 Oct.-1921 Sept. (Folder 8-10)
      - Austria-Budapest (Folder 11)
      - Poland-Warsaw (Folder 12)
    - Financial materials (Folder 13-16)
    - Financial materials (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
    - Organization and administration, 1920-1921 (Folder 4)
    - Personnel (Folder 5)
    - Reports. Director's status reports to New York and Paris (Folder 6)
    - Telegrams (Folder 7)
  - Agreements (Folder 8)
  - American Relief Administration
    - General (Folder 9)
    - International Committee for Relief Credits. Primarily reports relating to economic conditions in Europe (Folder 10)
  - Behrman, Major I.E. (Folder 11)
  - Bratislava Conference (Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Folder 13)
  - Coal
    - General. Statistics, reports, memoranda and correspondence (Folder 14)
    - General (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Austria (Folder 3)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 4)
    - Germany (Folder 5)
    - Hungary (Folder 6)
    - Prices (Folder 7)
    - Upper Silesia (Folder 8)
  - Czechoslovak government
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Food Ministry (Folder 10)
    - Foreign Affairs Ministry. Includes a summary of a speech by Eduard Benes, Minister of Foreign Affairs (Folder 11)
    - Railway Ministry (Folder 12)
  - Economic conditions (Folder 13)
  - Exports and imports (Folder 14)
  - Food
    - General. Primarily statistical reports (Folder 15)
    - Breadstuffs (Folder 16)
    - Decontrol
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 17)
      - England (Folder 18)
    - Flour (Folder 19)
    - Milk (Folder 20)
    - Russia (Folder 21)
    - Wheat (Folder 22)
  - Hoover War Library (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Hungary (Folder 2)
  - Hutchinson, Lincoln (Folder 3)
  - Industries (Folder 4)
  - Land reform (Folder 5)
  - Lutzaw, Countess (Folder 6)
  - Oil (Folder 7)
  - Population (Folder 8)
  - Railways (Folder 9)
  - Red Cross, American Junior (Folder 10)
  - Textiles (Folder 11)
  - United States Legation (Folder 12)
  - United States Trade Commissioner (Folder 13)
  - Upper Silesia (Folder 14)
- MISSION TO POLAND OFFICE FILES, 1918-1922
  - General (Box 32)
    - General. Relates to the telephone system (Folder 15)
    - Addresses (Folder 16)
    - Articles (Folder 17)
    - Blueprints (Folder 18)
    - Book orders and related correspondence (Folder 19)
    - Claims (Folder 20)
    - Clippings (Folder 21)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General. Alphabetical
          - A-F (Folder 22-27)
          - G-Z (Box 33, Folder 1-18)
        - New York Office
          - General (Folder 19)
          - Krueger, J.W. (Folder 20)
          - Poland, W.B. (Folder 21)
          - Sawtelle, R.H. (Folder 22)
          - Shattuck, E.P. (Folder 23)
          - Wescott, G.C. (Folder 24)
      - Barber, A.B. (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
      - Causey, W.B. (Folder 5-7)
      - Fisk, A.J. (Box 35, Folder 1-4)
      - Gabriel, H.R. (Folder 5)
      - Gaskill, C.S. (Folder 6-8)
      - Smith, H.B. (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
    - Financial materials
      - General
        - General. Includes material relating to the Edge Bill, amending the Federal Reserve Act with reference to foreign banking (Folder 5-7)
        - Relief credits (Folder 8)
        - Remittances (Folder 9)
      - Guaranty Trust (Folder 10)
      - Morgan-Harjes Company (Folder 11)
        - General (Folder 12)
        - Jay, W.D.
    - Forms (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Maps and diagrams (Folder 2)
    - Meeting materials (Folder 3)
    - Passes and passports (Folder 4)
    - Personnel materials (Folder 5-7)
    - Reports
      - General
        - General (Folder 8-10)
        - Monthly (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
      - Geological (Folder 3)
      - Mechanical (Folder 4)
    - Statistics
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Industrial (Folder 6)
    - Telegrams (Folder 7-10)
    - Telegrams (Box 39, Folder 1-7)
    - Telegrams (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
    - Trip materials (Berlin) (Folder 8)
  - Accidents (Folder 9)
  - Agreements, contracts, negotiations, treaties
    - General (Folder 10-11)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 12)
    - Danzig (Folder 13-14)
    - Germany. SEE ALSO: Coal/Agreements with Germany (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Hungary-Czechoslovakia (Folder 2)
  - Agriculture
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Crops
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Increased production (Folder 5)
      - Posen (Folder 6)
    - Education (Folder 7)
    - Fertilizers (Folder 8)
    - Machinery (Folder 9)
    - Polish Agricultural Society (Folder 10)
    - Soldiers, land settlement (Folder 11)
    - Uncultivated lands (Folder 12)
  - American Car and Foundry Company (Folder 13)
  - American Consulate, Warsaw (Folder 14)
  - American Embassy, Paris
    - General (Folder 15)
    - Harrison, Leland (Folder 16)
    - Logan, J.A. (Folder 17-20)
  - American Legation, Warsaw (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - American Polish Chamber of Commerce and Industry (Folder 2)
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Griffin, A. (Folder 4)
  - American Relief Administration
    - General (Folder 5)
    - European Children's Fund, Danzig
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Lange, J.H. (Folder 7)
    - European Children's Fund, London
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Bridges, A.R. (Folder 9)
      - Brown, Walter Lyman (Folder 10)
      - Owen, Herbert (Folder 11)
      - Quinn, C.J.C. (Folder 12)
    - European Children's Fund, Warsaw
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Baldwin, P.S. (Folder 14)
      - Fuller, W.P. (Folder 15)
      - White, J.C. (Folder 16)
    - Moscow (Folder 17)
    - New York
      - General (Folder 18)
      - Sherman, Roger (Folder 19)
    - Vienna (Folder 20)
    - Supplies (Folder 21)
  - Americans in Warsaw (Folder 22)
  - Approvisation
    - General (Folder 23)
    - Mining districts (Folder 24)
  - Atterbury, W.W. (Folder 25)
  - Attolico, S. (Folder 26)
  - Atwood, William G. (European Technical Advisers, Yugoslavia) (Folder 27)
  - Austrian troubles (Folder 28)
  - Automobiles
    - General (Folder 29)
    - Automobile Club (Folder 30)
    - Permits (Folder 31)
    - Supplies (Folder 32)
    - Transport (Folder 33)
  - Baldwin Locomotive Works (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Bodman, H.L. (Folder 2)
  - Bogdanovitsch, Charles (Folder 3)
  - Bojenski, Eugene (Folder 4)
  - Brawer, Lewis (Folder 5)
  - Bristol Hotel (Folder 6)
  - British Mission (Folder 7)
  - Brown, Marshall W. (Folder 8)
  - Bryant, M.C. (Folder 9)
  - Bulgaria (Folder 10)
  - Citizen's Repatriation League (Folder 11)
  - Coal
    - General
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Reports (Folder 13-14)
      - Statistics (Folder 15-16)
      - Statistics (Box 44, Folder 1)